in this lesson we're going to talk about
how to calculate the volume
of a cylinder
so let's say the radius of the cylinder
is 5 inches
and the height of the cylinder
let's say it's 10 inches
so using this information
what is the volume of the cylinder
the volume is pi r squared times height
it's basically the area of the base
times the height of the cylinder
so for any prism the volume is base
times height
the area of the base which is the area
of a circle that's pi r squared and so
it's pi r squared times h
in this example the radius is 5
and the height is 10.
5 squared is 25 and 25 times 10 is 250.
so the volume for this cylinder is 250
pi
and it's cubic inches
so that is the answer
now if you want to get the decimal value
of that answer
it's approximately
785.4
cubic inches
you